571- 242-1832 Reston, VA alasadi.ammar@gmail.com

ABOUT

I am a web developer with a background in languages and communication. My goal as a developer is to find creative solutions, designs and create the best user experience. I value communication and planning to guide my progress in web development. I am a team player with a passion for sharing and learning new technology.

EXPERIENCE

Web Development Immersive Student General Assembly, DC

March - June 2017

- learned web development in a fast paced environment with a focus on functional programming.
- Designed and developed full stack web applications using various languages, libraries and frameworks like Ruby on Rails and MEAN.
- Developed web applications in a team setting working in Agile environment.
- Adapted and established work flow utilizing version control like Git and GitHub.
- Improved on the reliability and readability of source code by following best practices.
- Improved on best practices in programming through feedback from colleges and instructors
- Practiced planning, modeling and wire framing applications.

Arabic Linguist PGLS - Fairfax, VA 2015 - 2017

- Translated materials in Arabic and English with a focus on accuracy and details.
- Worked with a team of translators to deliver projects, meet deadlines and guarantee client satisfaction.
- Managed a team of five translators and assigned tasks based on the skills of each team member.
- Developed cultural training guide for deployed government officials.

Arabic Interpreter Cyracom - Tuscon, AZ 2014 - 2017

- Provided interpretation and cultural perspective for medical, legal and government officials.
- Provided clients cultural education to help them make informed decisions.
- Created a fluid experience between parties and eliminated the language barrier.
- Received many compliments from clients and managers for providing exceptional customer service.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS3, DOM Agile/ Scrum JavaScript J Query OOP Angular React SQL and NoSQL ORM and ODM Ruby Ruby on Rails Sinatra **MVC** Routers API's **AJAX JSON** Postman

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Washington, DC Web Development Immersive Feb - June 2017

University of Technology

Baghdad, Iraq A.A. in Architecture Design 2006 - 2008